Finding Aid for Dance Marathon at the University of Michigan records, 1998-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Dance Marathon at the University of Michigan records 1998-2010
Dance Marathon at the University of Michigan
1.5 linear feet
2011081 Bimu 2
Dance Marathon at the University of Michigan is a student organization that raises funding for rehabilitation programs at children's hospitals of southeast Michigan. The collection includes yearbooks, scrapbooks, videos, and event guides.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Material was acquired from Dance Marathon in April 2011. (Donor no. 10524 ).
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
University of Michigan Dance Marathon was started in 1997 by students who wanted to support sick children and their families. The organization raises money and forms relationships with the children by hosting a number of events throughout the year, culminating in the main event in March, in which the student dancers are on their feet for a marathon of thirty hours. Proceeds from these events go to the C.S. Mott Children's Hospital in Ann Arbor and the William Beaumont Hospital in Royal Oak to fund rehabilitation programs for children, such as martial arts, horseback riding, and yoga.
In 2009 the organizational changed its name to Dance Marathon at the University of Michigan. The 2011 Dance Marathon raised over $447,000.
The records of Dance Marathon have been divided into three series: Event Material, Audiovisual Material, and Scrapbooks. These records document the organization's activities from 1998 to 2010.
The Event Material series consists of a dance captain's manual, news articles, promotional materials, sponsor packets, visitor's guides, and yearbooks. These files give a sense of Dance Marathon's mission and how its events were organized.
The Audiovisual Material series includes CDs, DVDs, and a VHS tape documenting its activities.
The Scrapbook series contains scrapbooks filled with photos of the events, student volunteers, and children with whom the organization has worked.
Subjects:
Charities--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Dance.; University of Michigan--Students--Societies, etc.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and custons--1991-2000.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and custons--2001-2010.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Charities--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Dance.; University of Michigan--Students--Societies, etc.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and custons--1991-2000.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and custons--2001-2010.
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.; Videotapes.; DVDs
- Event Material
  - Dance Captain Manual, 2010-2011 (Box 1)
  - News Articles, 1998, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Promotional Materials, 2009-2010 (Box 1)
  - Sponsor Packets, 2009-2011 (Box 1)
  - Visitor's Guides, 2007-2010 (Box 1)
  - Yearbooks, 2000-2010, 2 folders (Box 1)
- Audiovisual Material
  - Memory Videos and Photo, CD (Box 1)
  - Dance Marathon: Making Kids Smile, Maize and Blue Style, 2004-2005, DVD (Box 1)
  - 1998 (VHS) (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks
  - 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - 2002 (Box 2)
  - 2003 (Box 2)
  - 2004 (Box 2)
  - 2005-2006 (Box 2)